Dean Phillip Jones

16 Woodstock Rd SW, Calgary, AB | (587)433-5825 djones_09_riseball@hotmail.com | LinkedIn | Codewars | GitHub

Career Objective

To undertake a challenging career opportunity where I can utilize my versatility and experience in a dynamic work environment. I am a motivated and detail orientated professional that exceeds expectations and delivers quality results on-time. Multi-skilled and a diligent team member, I possess strong technical and analytical skills that would be an asset to your team.

Skills and Software

ons
ce
g

Skills and Experience

- Strong data fluency and automation.
- Successfully worked in a fast-paced environment.
- Continually exceeded expectations and delivered quality results on-time.
- Demonstrated ability to pick-up new software quickly.

Back-End Development:

- Generated full CRUD for SQL database integrations utilizing parameterized queries for security.
- Implemented validation class library for efficient use across multiple projects.
- Created custom DLL library in C# with full unit testing to ensure proper functionality.

Front-End Development:

- Proven experience implementing responsive designs for websites.
- Proficient at combining functional and creative layouts for graphical user interfaces.

Additional Skills:

- Strong team leader with good communication skills and English fluency.
- Passionate about data, logic theory and fundamental programming principles.

Team Skills:

- Developed automated scripts to effectively saving hundreds of man-hours.
- Experience maintaining setup of in-house software systems creating a coherent work environment.
- Trained and mentored a large office providing excellent software support.
- Documented official standards and software specifications.
- Successfully worked remotely for over two years.

Education

SAIT - OOSD - Object Oriented Software Developer Certification
Codecademy Pro - Programming with Python Certification
Jul

Oct 2016 - July 2017 Jul 2018 - Oct 2018

Employment History

CaManSol Ltd. - Software Developer

Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Developed a front-end web application using ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery for displaying a Navisworks XML file clash report.
- Integrated existing MVVM DLL library to parse XML files and provided feedback for errors.
- Incorporated full CRUD File Manager to handle uploading of XML files and project folders.
- Created fully responsive design and UI using W3CSS, Font Awesome icons and a custom font.
- Performed routine tests to eliminate bugs.

Willow Park Wines & Spirits - Practicum - Junior Software Developer May 2017 - July 2017

- Evaluated and developed desktop application for the integration of their eCommerce website to the accounting system using C#.
- Troubleshooted and resolved website's SOAP API response errors.
- Automation and mapping of data between into MySQL database.
- Generated custom reports from exported CSV accounting data for external client.

Three Streams Engineering - CAD Support Specialist

July 2012 - Feb 2015

- Participated on daily CAD tickets servicing a large office supporting multiple software and disciplines.
- Provided final CAD software system installation, setup and configurations.
- Mentored and advised junior drafters.
- Developed and modified AutoLISP scripts used for automating batch file cleanup.
- Generated MS-SQL reports for weekly model reviews.
- Consistently delivered solutions and troubleshooted complex problems.
- Worked remotely long distance for over two years.